Guide to the Records of the Vice President of External Affairs, Naomi Levine 1975-1986 RG 7.0
New York University Archives
Records of Office of the Vice President for External Affairs (Naomi Levine)
1975-1986
RG 7.0
New York University Archives
3.0 linear feet 3 linear feet (3 boxes)
Naomi Levine came to New York University in 1980. She became the Vice President of External Affairs and led a $2 billion dollar fundraising campaign in her 22 years of service. The following collection includes some of her correspondences and papers relating to the Office of External Affairs.
Levine, Naomi B., 1923-
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject heading then chronologically within each subject heading.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
I, General
Physical Access
Please note that this collection is stored offsite, and you must contact the repository to schedule access.
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains one linear foot of materials dated 1975-1986.
The records contain correspondence, development initiatives and budget information involving the Office of External Affairs and including personal papers/letters belonging to Naomi Levine.
Historical/Biographical Note
While Naomi Levine is well known for her highly successful tenure as a fundraiser at New York University, she is also an accomplished lawyer, historian, author and owner/founder of a girls’ camp in Upstate New York. A graduate of Hunter College and Columbia Law School, Levine went on to hold several positions at the American Jewish Congress (AJC). She was the Executive Director of AJC from 1971-1978, making her the first female in charge of a major Jewish organization.
Levine came to N.Y.U. in 1980, after deciding to take on a new direction: fundraising. Naomi Levine’s fundraising efforts helped N.Y.U. raise $2 billion in her 22 years of service, including individual gifts of $30 million from Leonard Stern, $25 million from the Tisch Family, $15 million from Helen and Martin Kimmel and an estate from Sir Harold Acton valued at approximately $500 million. Due to Levine’s fundraising techniques, New York University has gone from raising about $20 million a year in 1978 to over $350 million a year at present. At N.Y.U., Levine also started the Center for Philanthropy and Fundraising and the Bronfman Center for Jewish Life and she continues to play an active role in both centers. Furthermore, Naomi Levine is a special advisor to University President, John Sexton, on matters of external affairs and fundraising.
Sources:
Naomi Levine, Biographical File
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Provenance
The records were transferred to the University Archives by the Office of External Affairs.
New York University. Office of Public Affairs.; New York University. Office of University Development and Alumni Relations.; New York University.; Budgets.; Correspondence.; Educational fund raising.; New York (State) |z New York.; Programs (documents).; Universities and colleges |x Administration.; Universities and colleges |x Finance.
- Inventory
  - Alumni Federation, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bobst Dinner, 1 of 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bobst Dinner, 2 of 2, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commencement, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Commencement, 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Commencement, 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Commencement, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Commencement, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dental School, 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dental School, 1 of 2, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dental School, 2 of 2, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Development, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Development, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Development, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Development, 1 of 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Development, 2 of 2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)